Guide to the David S. Brown papers, 1915-1989 MS0001.UA
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
- Scrapbooks, 1915-1985; MS0001 Series 11; 50 Linear feet
  - Scrapbook 22, 01/1963 --10/1963 (Box 63)
    A maroon scrapbook (12" x 15" x 1 1/2") containing family photographs, postcards of vacation photographs from Puerto Rico and St. Thomas, family cards and letters, playbills from local Washington theaters, newsletters from the Brown children's schools, and the cover of the program from the 23rd annual Ice Capades. Professional memorabilia of Brown's includes 8 x10 photographs of Brown giving lectures,an announcement of the election of Brown to the Vice Presidency of Leadership Resources Inc., program pages from the April "1963 National Conference on Public Administration", postcards and bulletin pages from Indiana University where Brown was a visiting professor and an article from Panorama June 1963 on Brown and a Pakistani student at George Washington University. Of historical interest are January 1963 articles on a record snowstorm in Maine, a magazine cover from May 1963 picturing the astronaut Cooper, magazine photographs of Pope John XXIII at his death on June 7, 1963, magazine photographs of Pope Paul VI, pages from the New York Times Magazine picturing those who had received the president's "freedom medal", and a Washington Post article of September 25, 1963 entitled "Senate Ratifies Test Ban Treaty." Also historically interesting are clippings, information pamphlets and other memorabilia from the solar eclipse of July 20, 1963, as well as an obituary for Paul H. Appleby, 2nd Dean of the Maxwell School of Syracuse University. Important material concerning the Washington, D.C. area includes a copy of the TWIG, a publication of the Jr. Auxillary of Alexandria Hospital as well as programs and photographs from the Auxillary's 30th annual ball. Newspaper clippings on an August flash flood in Alexandria in addition to magazine photos of the 1963 march on Washington also detail area history.
  - Scrapbook 23, 10/1963 --02/1964 (Box 64)
    This green scrapbook (12" x 15" x 1 1/2") contains extensive material on the assassination of President John F. Kennedy. A magazine pictorial on John F. Kennedy and his family, magazine photographs of the assassination in Dallas as well as magazine photographs of the president's funeral and Lyndon Johnson's swearing in are included. Other historically significant material includes an invitation to the presentation of the president's "Medals of Freedom" on December 6, 1963 one of which was received by Robert A. Lovett. Articles on Roberat A. Lovett and his award as well as magazine photographs of Pope Paul IV in the Holy Land are also present. Family memorabilia includes flyers from the Brown children's schools as well as programs from the schools' sporting events, Christmas cards and photographs. Professional memorabilia of Brown's includes articles he authored and programs from various professional meetings. Materials about the Washington area includes a program from a performance at George Washington University's Lisner auditorium, clippings from George Washington University Newsletters, as well as an 8 x 10 photograph of the National Christmas tree. Another interesting item in the scrapbook is a collection of PTA letters from St. Stephen's school in Alexandria, Virginia authored by Brown on the topic of "Adolescence" and a speech on that subject given by Dr. Phillips of George Washington University.
  - Scrapbook 24, 05/1964 --10/1964 (Box 65)
    A blue scrapbook (12" x 15" x 1 1/2") containing family photographs and the architect's blueprints for the Brown family's summer home in Maine. Professional material of Brown's contained in this scrapbook includes a bibliography of Brown's professional writings, newspaper clippings mentioning the work of Brown as well as various research papers of Brown's. Some of the material included in the scrapbook deals with George Washington University such as clippings from George Washington University's faculty newsletter, a newspaper article detailing the fact that President Eisenhower was to be awarded an honorary degree at George Washington University's commencement in 1964, clippings from the George Washington University magazine Federal Issue, and, in addition obituaries for George Washington University president T. H. Carroll. Of historical interest are baseball souvenir scorecards from 1964, a playbill from the Plymouth Theater, magazine pictures of General Douglas McArthur's funeral, a booklet entitled "Tribute to Eleanor Roosevelt with her photograph on its cover, and a magazine photograph of the Indian statesman Nehru's funeral. Also included are tickets and a program from the USGA 64th open championship golfing tournament, magazine photographs of the 1964 World's Fair, a June 1964 article entitled "Senate Stops Filibuster on Rights Bill" dealing with the stalling of a civil rights bill by some Congressmen as well as white House invitations to a reception given by Lady Bird Johnson. Three other historically interesting items include memorabilia from the 1964 Campaign Conference for Democratic Women, an April 30, 1964 press release titled "Remarks of the President to 1964 Campaign Conference", as well as a three dimensional color picture with the handwritten notation "1st 3-d color picture". The scrapbook also contains several brochures from Washington are landmarks such as the Shrine of the Immaculate Conception, Washington Cathedral, Franciscan Monastery, Harper's Ferry, John Brown Wax Museum, Antietam battlefield, Mount Vernon and Gadsby's Tavern.
  - Scrapbook 25, 10/1964 --05/1965 (Box 66)
    A blue scrapbook (15" x 12" x 1.5") containing family photographs, Christmas and Valentine cards, wedding announcements of friends of the Browns, postcards to family members during business trips, several 'Peanuts' comic strips as well as memorabilia from the Brown Children's athletic events.
  - Scrapbook 26, 1965 (Box 67)
    A black scrapbook contains photos, news paper clippings, and a System and Procedure Journal of May 1965. Moreover, it also contains Brown's and family photos at Long Island, Maine, Compobello Island, Blue Nose, Windsor, Canada, Wyo valley, wedding of John and Joan Sylvester at Lucerne Inn, football match of St. Stephan vs Georgetown, and St. Agnes school spring festival.
  - Scrapbook 27, 10/1965 --07/1966 (Box 68)
    This brown scrapbook contains different news paper clippings including articles by Mr. brown. Photos of Chris at 17 and his graduation, Hockey Day at St. Agnes, Trip to Florida, Christmas Day, fishing at Rochester with Bob Brown, Lyn in hospital and places like James town, Norfolk, Botanical Garden. Get Well cards to Lyn, Christmas cards to the Browns and copy of the 112th Cyracus University Commencement.
  - Scrapbook 28, 08/1968 --06/1968 (Box 69)
    This brown scrapbook contains photos of Mr. Brown's family, Adelle's Locust Valley visit, Visit to Anderson college at Rchobatu, Evie's childhood, Christmas, Mr. Brown's 25th Wedding Anniversary, his new cottage, with Senator Jackson, Kimbal store, and family home. Mr. Browns membership cards, a letter from Mrs. Lyndon B. Johnson, the former President's wife. The obituary of Evelyn Brown (1967) and death of Robert F. Kennedy (1968) is also included.
  - Scrapbook 29, 1968 (Box 69)
    This green scrapbook contains photos of Dr. Brown's marriage to Anne Elizon Brown, including those at church, receptions. Photos from visits to Quebec, family photos at different places including Campobello Island, Lac du Flambeau, Maine, Thanksgiving and Adele at St. Timothy.
  - Scrapbook 30, 1969 (Box 70)
    A reddish, brown scrapbook (14.75" x 12.25" x 1.5") in poor condition. It contains mostly pictures of DSB and family. Among the photographs included are pictures of family vacations, holidays, and other family events. In addition there are newspaper clippings on Charles de Gaulle's resignation as president of France, Eisenhower's death, and the lunar landing.
  - Scrapbook 31, 1970 (Box 70)
    This scrapbook (14.25" x 12.125" x 1.5") has a bright red cover. In it are pictures of DSB at speaking engagements, of graduations (children), DSB's wedding anniversary, and of the family dog Ralph. There are also many personal letters between DSB and family and an invitation to testify in front of Congress.
  - Scrapbook 32, 1971 (Box 71)
    This lime green scrapbook (14.25" x 12.125" x 1.5") holds a lot of invitations to events(daughter Adele's graduation and other professional events). There are also pictures of Adele's graduation as well as pictures from their European Vacation England, France, Yugoslavia, Austria) and from Christmas.
  - Scrapbook 33, 1972 (Box 72)
    A marbled - brown scrapbook (16.00" x 14.00" x 1.5") with plenty of greeting cards from different holidays (Father's & Mother's day, Valentines day, birthday, Christmas, Easter, and anniversary). There are professional writings and descriptions of DSB. Finally there are clippings of J. Edger Hoover's and Truman's death.
  - Scrapbook 34, 1973 (Box 72)
    A marbled - brown scrapbook (16.00" x 14.00" x 1.5") with several theater programs and personal letters. Pictures include those of birthdays, holidays, and a few special events (balls,etc). There are clippings of LBJ's and Picasso's death and of the Watergate scandal.
  - Scrapbook 35, 1974 (Box 73)
    A dark green scrapbook (16.25" x 13.5" x 3") containing news clippings on local events, Watergate, the Energy Crisis, and the SR-71(a supersonic spy plane). There are pictures of the yearly retreat to Maine summer cottage, of special days (e.g. Christmas, Valentines day, etc.) and of the yearly vacation to Europe (this time to Portugal, Andorra, and France).
  - Scrapbook 36, 1975 (Box 74)
    This brown scrapbook (16.25" x 13.50 x 1.75") has news clippings of the Watergate participants that were found guilty (i.e. Mitchell, Halteman, Maridian, Ehrlichman), of talks between Ford and British Prime Minister Wilson, Saigon's surrender to North Vietnam, and sporadic local events. There are also mementoes from a local vacation to Williamsburg, from Chris's wedding to Connie, from Adele's graduation from College, from the trip to Maine, and from the marriage of DSB jr. There are pictures of all these events as well.
  - Scrapbook 37, 1976 (Box 75)
    This brown scrapbook (16.50" x 13.50" x 2.50") contains several mementoes from the 200th anniversary of the United States including postcards and a special issue of Time magazine. There are pictures of birthdays, vacation in Virginia, DSB's trip to EL Salvador and Mexico, vacation to Ireland, marriage of Robert Brown and Christmas. Finally there are clippings of Carter and his campaign, an excavation led by Chris Brown, the death of Mao Tse Tung, and the Concord Supersonic Passenger Jet.
  - Scrapbook 38, 1977 (Box 76)
    In this brown scrapbook (16.25" x 13.50" x 2.50") there are pictures of the usual birthdays and events (Valentine's day, Mother's day, Christmas, and Trip to Maine). There are also clippings of Jimmy Carter's inauguration, death of Elvis, construction of Alaskan Pipeline, and the Egypt-Israel Peace Agreement.
  - Scrapbook 39, 1978 (Box 77)
    This dark brown scrapbook (16.25" x 13.50" x 2") contains clippings of Hubert Humphrey's death, of a snowstorm in D.C., and Pope Paul VI's death. There are pictures of the snowstorm, family birthdays (including Anne's 37), vacation to Grand Canyon and Las Vegas and France, social events, public speaking events featuring DSB, and Christmas.
  - Scrapbook 40, 1979 (Box 78)
    In this dark brown scrapbook (16.25" x 13.50" x 2") there are several clippings of the Washington D.C. snowstorm, the Egypt-Israel peace Agreement, sports articles, obituaries of acquaintances, professional publications, trip to Quebec, the installment of Margaret Thatcher, and the takeover of US embassy in Teheran. The pictures include Rob and Anne's and DSB's birthday, trip to Harper's ferry, Valentines Day, trip to London and Scotland, and Christmas.
  - Scrapbook 41, 1980 (Box 79)
    This brown scrapbook (16.00" x 13.25" x 2.00") contains many pictures of DSB's trip to Massachusetts, California, Yosemite, Washington, Poland, Denmark, Norway, Holland, Belgium, Luxembourg, France, and Vienna. There are clippings of earthquakes, Mt. St. Helens eruption, GWU expansion, 1980 election and boycott of the Olympics. Additionally there are pictures of family get-togethers (birthday, visits, and Christmas).
  - Scrapbook 42, 1981 (Box 80)
    This brown scrapbook (16.25" x 13.50" 1.5") contains clippings of DSB's speech at NCSA, an article in the Washington Post, several professional articles, death of one of DSB's students, Reagan's inauguration, death of GW official, safari in Kenya, Tanzania, and Sudan (Postcards and maps of the area), attempted assassination of Reagan, first flight of space shuttle, Di and Charles's wedding, Sandra Day O'Connor's appointment, Sadat's assassination, and Poland's military takeover. There are a few pictures of mother's day, his safari, and Christmas.
  - Scrapbook 43, 1982 (Box 81)
    This black scrapbook (14.50" x 11.25" x 2") with a broken spine contains pictures of new grandchildren (Kim), DSB's trip to Georgia and Maine, family birthdays, Valentines day, Mother's and Father's day, and Christmas. There are also clippings of an airplane crash, sports events, George Washington University's academic standing, the First edition of the Washington Times, Al Haig's resignation, and of DSB's book release.
  - Scrapbook 44, 1983 (Box 82)
    This black scrapbook (14.50" x 11.25" x 2") contains more pictures of DSB's trip to Georgia, Rob's birthday, DSB shoveling snow, the European vacation (Iceland, Paris, Hungary, Italy, Czechoslovakia, and West Germany), and Christmas. There are clippings of the Redskin's Super Bowl victory, the snow storm in D.C., Nolan Ryan's new career strikeout record, the shooting down of the Korean 747, Grenada Invasion, the hostages in Lebanon and mementoes from the European vacation.
  - Scrapbook 45, 1983-1984 (Box 83)
    A black scrapbook (14"x11.5"x2") containing family photographs, newspaper clippings and some articles written by Dr. Brown. Also contains clippings and photographs of Dr. Brown celebrating the 30th Anniversary of the programs in Public Administration at G.W.. Besides, the scrapbook contains a list of books Dr. Brown read from August 20, 1983 to August 19, 1984 (138 to be exact!)
  - Scrapbook 46, 1981-1988 (Box 84)
    This scrapbook (14"x11"x2") contains a mixture of family pictures, newspaper clippings and articles written by Dr. Brown, ranging from 1981 to 1988. There is a tribute to Dr. Brown, honoring him as founder of the Public Administration Programs at G.W. and awarding him the Distinguished Service Award. Also, there are pictures of the Class of 1936 50th Alumni Reunion at the University of Maine (Dr. Brown's Alma Mater). It also contains clippings about the publication of his book: "Management's Hidden Enemy-and what can be done about it."
  - Scrapbook 46B, 1985 (Box 85)
    Contains family photographs, greeting cards, newspaper clippings and articles.
  - Scrapbook 47, 1982 (Box 85)
    (many duplicates)
  - Scrapbook 48, 1982 (Box 86)
  - Scrapbook 49, 1987 (Box 97)